hey everyone it's great to have you back
on my channel
for those of you who are new here my
name is Chrissy and I am a game designer
today's video is all about the
fascinating world of artificial
intelligence and how it can be used to
enhance game design
as we all know AI is one of the most
exciting technology calmed down I just
wanted to welcome everyone to this video
about using AI for my game design we're
not going to dive deep into AI Theory
here and I'm not going to explain what
Chet gbt is because I'm sure most of you
already know but I will tell you how I
use it together with a IR generators
like mid-chourney to create my game the
lost hotel
foreign
AI is currently a mega hype it is very
controversial in the art scene and
probably triggers some Fierce and scary
feelings many people also use it to
create art texts even books poems code
and more the first thing I did with AI
was to use it for some concept drawings
of the hotel and different areas and
rooms I use different art generators
like mid-choney Dolly 2 night Cafe and
dream by wombu because I couldn't put my
imagination perfectly on paper and I
needed inspiration for color palettes
and atmosphere with these generators I
could describe what I wanted to see and
then I got more suggestions to continue
with until I had a concept artwork that
was very close to my imagination here
you can see some of the hotter
spaceships I had designed by mid-journey
I like the atmosphere and the details
and here is my sketch based on the
concept art
here you go uh yeah well the most
exciting moment was when I used open eye
chat TBT for the first time I had heard
a lot about it before but I couldn't
imagine what it was really like so I
just typed in a request to construct a
story about a spaceship hotel with a
Time Loop and a plot twist which is the
story of my game in a nutshell what I
got was stunning I changed a few things
according to what I had already drafted
introduced it to some of my characters
and Concepts and after a day of not
believing what I was doing and getting a
lot of brain chatubity became my
full-time collaborator thank you for
your kind words as an AI language model
I don't have a concept of employment or
rewards but I'm always here to assist
you with any questions or concerns you
may have
I'm glad to be of service okay okay stop
it had a lot of information stored
within the chat session so I could
always ask it to remember things we had
already discussed like character
backstories and item descriptions
sometimes it's a bit off when it
suddenly makes up new names for my
character which is confusing and makes
me doubt it's intelligence but it's a
great help to me in writing texts
descriptions new ideas puzzles
connections between characters and
events even how some areas should look
like to suit a certain mood it gives me
examples for puzzles of how the player
can convince NPCs to make certain
decisions or what I could design to
achieve a certain goal and what game
mechanics I could use it even suggested
the rules were space chess game and for
a fictional sport from the planet
Proxima Centauri B LOL nice oh by the
way as a non-native speaker I find it
hard to come up with good texts to
Market my game and make them concise
to do that for me too and yes I also get
head translating the text for my videos
it started off pretty well and the more
I added like make it more exciting the
more I like the result I use the text
for my upcoming pages on patreon Steam
and Kickstarter hey the AI could even
write the Game design document for me
how's that huh no connection on this
number hmm that's what I thought
here's a little collection of AI
generated concept art for the lobby
the AI helped me translate a specific
mode into my pixel art but I wouldn't
say they're exactly what I wanted it
inspired me a little bit to create an
atmosphere though
here is the part of the lobby I finished
so far at the end of the video there
will be a speed painting of it I hope
you like it
I added my finished Lobby pixel art into
mid-journey and had to generate some
similar pixel art and look at that it's
exactly how I wanted the hotel to look I
mean it doesn't look perfect or
pixelated but I like the colors the
lights the plants oh my God look at them
the overall style of these images is
beautiful I will definitely try to
switch the colors and I will add some
more decoration especially plants
in my game the player takes the role of
the hotel manager and before there were
eight of them trying to manage when I
wanted to design this eight former Hotel
years I wanted each of them to have a
special key and correspond to one of
nine special personality types so I
asked chatubiti to describe all that and
I got some pretty good ideas that I
could use I also had an idea in my head
for their appearance except for one of
them the sixth hotelier who I plan to be
a loyal and disciplined person I entered
a vague description into the AI
generators and used to result as
inspiration here's my version and here
are all 8 hotel years and their keys
good job well done by the way do you say
please and thank you to AI I don't want
to be the one killed in the robot
Revolution I want them to see me as a
friend don't worry don't worry
all in all I think AI generators and
chatbots are a big step forward for the
world especially in terms of creative
work and I'm sure there's a lot more to
come in the near future for solo
developers like me it is a great help in
developing a game even in a creative
flow AI can motivate you to get back to
work and create something I'm even
considering letting it help me write
code and test later on
I'm excited to see what else we can
create with the help of artificial
creativity what do you think about it do
you think I art is real art would you
play a game completely designed by an AI
or is it all too sus for you
next time I will finally talk about the
story of the lost hotel and how the game
mechanic will be like until then enjoy
the speed picks link have a nice day and
choose
thank you
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
all right
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
thank you
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
thank you
foreign